James Allen

Website Designer & Developer

Portfolio: www.james-allen.ca Email: me@james-allen.ca Cell: (403) 702-2795

Highly motivated and versatile website developer with 10 years of professional experience. Almost exclusively self-taught having developed a passion for website development in the 4th grade. Currently pursuing a new full-time permanent or contract position with a focus on UI/UX design and/or frontend development.

Technology

HTML5 **AJAX** SVN (Tortoise) CSS3 / SCSS / Bootstrap / Bulma Drupal 7 / Drupal Commerce Photoshop Javascript / jQuery / Angular / Vue Magento Linux (Kubuntu) PHP / Zend / CodeIgniter Mailchimp API Windows MySQL / Postgre Paypal API Agile / SCRUM NodeJS / Gulp WAMP / LAMP

Experience

Contract Web Consultant

Self-Employed, January 2009 - Present

- Provide a variety of website production services including design, development, and SEO.
- Majority of incoming work is referral based or repeat business.
- Basic bookkeeping duties (estimates, invoices, receipts, etc).

AthleteBook

Contract Web Developer, April 2017 – July 2017

- Translated existing design PSD files in to usable visual components and Laravel Blade templates.
- Managed new and existing workflow for an overseas development team utilizing Agile and JIRA.
- Designed several visual components to be aesthetically congruent with existing design work.
- Designed and developed single page promotional websites.

Renoworks

UI/UX Designer & Frontend Developer, June 2014 – April 2017

- Lead designer for new user interfaces.
- Converted client-provided designs in to templates and visual components compatible with the Renoworks Enterprise platform.
- Conceptualized and developed the first proof-of-concept for the Renoworks "Color Picker" phone app. This opened the door for Renoworks in to more native phone application development.

- Lead the charge on developing fully mobile-responsive templates for the existing application in my spare time with another developer.
- Was the "Go to guy" in the office for any HTML5 or CSS3 related questions or issues.

Western Inspection

Website & Web Application Developer, February 2013 - May 2014

- Tasked with developing a new, cross-platform capable, browser-based business software.
- Consult and assist in the eventual replacement of workstation and server infrastructure from a Windows 2000 platform to a Linux based system.
- Maintained and regularly tested commercial alarm system.

open2space

Contract Web Developer, June 2011 - March 2012

- Worked closely with a team developing layouts, views, and controllers in Zend PHP for an enterprise level client.
- Gained a solid understanding of MVC principles.
- Developed and maintained a number of small Drupal 6 & 7 websites for new and existing clients.

StyleLabs Marketing Group

Contract Production Manager April 2010 – October 2010

- Liason between marketing and development team. Translated marketing objectives in to development tasks.
- Played a key role in the conceptualization and initial development of a proprietary CMS.
- Managed workflow for a small team consisting of myself, a junior developer, and a graphic designer.

Reliance Protectron

Full-time Contract Production Manager, April 2009 – February 2010

- Responded to daily tickets for servicing, diagnosing, repairing, and installing alarm systems in residential and commercial settings.
- Extremely familiar with the DSC 1550/55 & 1832/48/64 boards, and GE Simon models.
- Some experience with Ademco/Honeywell, Paradox, and 2Gig systems as well.
- Top Calgary technician for up-selling peripheral devices, upgrades, and renewals.

Cambrian House

Junior Web Developer, April 2009 - February 2010

- Worked on a variety of different small start-up website projects launched from Cambrian House's crowdsourcing platform.
- Converted PSD's from the design team in to HTML and CSS websites.
- Worked to ensure cross-browser compatibility between major browsers.
- Discovered and helped patch a security vulnerability on the company's public forum software.

Education

Interaction Design Foundation Web Design for Usability Course (online)

Foothills Composite High School 06' High School Diploma InfoPro I,II,III; Computer Programming II, III 2005 Skills Alberta – Bronze – Website Design